The method I recommend for implementing
在实现有效的 LCS 算法时
an efficient LCS algorithm is using a matrix and dynamic programming.
建议采用矩阵和动态规划法
Dynamic programming is all about breaking
动态规划是指将更大的问题
a larger problem into a smaller set of subproblems,
拆分成多个子问题
and building up a complete solution without having to repeat any subproblems.
并创建一个完整的解决方案 不需要重复解决子问题
This approach assumes that you can split up
这种方法假设你可以将大的 LCS 任务
a large LCS task into a combination of smaller tasks.
拆分成更小的任务并组合起来
Let's look at a simple example that compares letters,
举个简单的字母比较例子
the answer ABCD, and the source BD.
假设答案是“ABCD”原文是“BD”
We can see right away that the longest sub-sequence of letters here is two.
一眼就能看出最长的字母子序列是 2
B and D are in sequence in both strings.
B 和 D 在两个字符串中都按顺序出现了
We can calculate this by looking at relationships between each letter in the two strings.
我们可以通过查看两个字符串中每个字母之间的关系算出这个结果
This technique can be applied to individual words as well,
这种技巧也可以应用到单个字词上
not just individual letters.
而不仅仅是单个字母上
Here, I have a matrix with the answer letters
在这个矩阵中 答案字母位于顶部
on top and the source letters on the left side.
原文字母位于左侧
This starts out as a matrix that has as many columns and rows as letters in the strings,
这个矩阵的列数和行数为字符串中的字母数量
plus one additional row and column,
再加上一行和一列
filled with zeros on the top and left sides.
并在顶部和左侧填充了 0
So in this case, instead of a two-by-four matrix,
所以现在不是 2x4 矩阵
it's a three-by-five matrix.
而是 3x5 矩阵
Now, we can fill this matrix up by breaking it into smaller LCS problems.
下面将问题拆分成更小的 LCS 问题并填充矩阵
For example, let's first look at the shortest sub-strings.
例如 先查看最短的子字符串
The starting letter of A and S. Well, first ask.
A 和 S 的起始字母
What is the longest common subsequence between these two letters, A and B?
A 和 B 这两个字母之间最长的公共子序列是什么？
Since these letters don't match,
因为这两个字母不匹配
the answer is zero,
所以答案是 0
and I'll fill in the corresponding grid cell with that value.
在相应的单元格里填上 0
Then we ask the next question.
然后看看下个问题
What is the LCS between AB and B?
AB 和 B 之间的 LCS 是多少？
Here, we have a match, B and B,
现在 B 和 B 匹配了
and we can fill in the appropriate value, one.
在相应的单元格中填上值 1
Notice that I'm only looking at if there's a matching letter between
注意 我一次仅查看
one column and one row at a time to get this one match.
一列与一行是否有匹配的字母并获得匹配值
If we continue along this row,
如果继续沿着这行查看
we can actually see that B only matches this one time,
可以看到 B 仅这一次会匹配
and any further questions such as what does the LCS between ABCD and B?
对于后面的问题 例如 ABCD 和 B 之间的 LCS 是多少？
We'll have that same value,
值都是 1
one, due to the initial BB match.
因为一开始 B 和 B 匹配
In fact, this one will propagate to the right,
实际上 这个 1 将扩散到右侧
filling up the rest of this row.
使这行剩余的单元格也填写 1
So let's move on to the second row.
再看看第二行
A and BD have zero matches,
A 和 BD 不匹配
then AB and BD do have a match,
然后 AB 和 BD 的确匹配
but this b row and d column do not match exactly.
但是这个 B 行和 D 列不匹配
The match actually comes from the same BB match that we recorded before,
这种匹配实际上来自之前记录的 BB 匹配
which we noted in the cell above this one.
我们在上面的单元格中记录下来了
So we can take that value one and pull it down into the cell.
所以可以将该值扩散到下面的单元格中
Then it stays one in this row until another match is finally reached,
在这行继续保持为 1 直到最终找到另一个匹配项
the letter D. With this additional match,
即字母 D 第二次匹配后
we add one to our previous highest LCS value to get
我们将之前最高的 LCS 值加一
a longest common subsequence of two at the corner of this filled matrix.
得出最长的公共子序列为 2 并填在矩阵的右下角
So to get our final value,
要获得最终结果
we then just have to normalize by dividing by the length of the answer text,
只需除以答案文本的长度来归一化
which has four letters,
答案有 4 个字母
so we get a final value of 0.5.
所以最终值为 0.5
A few interesting patterns emerge from this matrix.
这个矩阵有几个比较有意思的地方
We notice that the LCS is always going to be in the bottom right of our complete matrix,
我们发现 LCS 始终位于完整矩阵的右下角
because this corner indicates that we've reached the end of both of our texts.
因为右下角表明我们已经到达两个文本的结尾
We've considered all possible matches.
我们已经考虑了所有可能的匹配情况
Now, we started with a row and column of zeros.
我们从包含 0 的行和列开始
Then to fill up this matrix,
在填充该矩阵时
we looked at one cell at a time,
我们一次查看一个单元格
I'll call this our cell of interest,
我将此单元格称为感兴趣单元格
and we only had to handle two cases: One,
我们只需处理两种情形情形一
if we do not find a match as in the case of the letters A and B,
如果不匹配 例如字母 A 和 B
we can take a look at the values in the cells
则查看紧挨着感兴趣单元格的
directly to the left and top of our cell of interest,
左侧和顶部单元格中的值
then fill our cell by looking at the maximum of those two values.
然后用这两个值的最大值填充感兴趣单元格
In this case, the maximum is zero.
在此矩阵中 最大值为 0
Two, our second case is if we do find a match as in
情形二 如果发现匹配项
the case of B and B and D and D at the end.
即 B 和 B 以及最后的 D 和 D
In this case, we can take the value in the cell that is to
我们获取感兴趣单元格左上角的单元格中的值
the top left of our cell of interest and add one to fill our cell of interest.
并使其加一后填充到感兴趣单元格中
These two cases for no match and match,
我们可以通过这种不匹配和匹配情况
allow us to fill in the matrix dynamically.
动态地填充矩阵
To calculate each new cell value,
为了计算每个新的单元格值
we only have to look at one or two existing values in our matrix.
我们只需查看矩阵中一个或两个现有的值
Basically, taking earlier solutions to
即利用 LCS 任务之前的解决方案
LCS tasks and using them to build up a final solution.
得出最终的解决方案